(Episode 25 Fear Not, Let's Go Home)
(الحلقة 25 لا تخف ، لنذهب إلى المنزل)
It fits quite well.
انها مناسبة تماما.
Thank you, Uncle.
أشكرك عمي.
I just bought this.
لقد اشتريت هذا للتو.
It's brand new.
انها العلامة التجارية الجديدة.
Fine, let's sleep.
حسنًا ، دعنا ننام.
Why don't you get in bed?
لماذا لا تدخل السرير؟
I'm not sleepy yet.
لم أشعر بالنعاس بعد.
I'm not that sleepy either.
أنا لست نعسانًا أيضًا.
Before you go to bed,
قبل ان تذهب الى السرير،
what do you like to do?
ماذا تريد ان تفعل؟
Reading, usually.
القراءة عادة.
Reading.
قراءة.
Reading is good.
القراءة جيدة.
(Practical Introduction to Electrical Engineering)
(مقدمة عملية في الهندسة الكهربائية)
I only have textbooks about electronics here.
لدي فقط كتب مدرسية عن الإلكترونيات هنا.
Can you still read it?
هل ما زلت تستطيع قراءتها؟
I can.
أنا استطيع.
Don't you get sleepy reading this kind of book?
ألا تشعر بالنعاس من قراءة هذا النوع من الكتب؟
No.
رقم.
(Practical Introduction to Electrical Engineering)
(مقدمة عملية في الهندسة الكهربائية)
Uncle.
اخو الام.
(Chair, 90 percent new Table, 80 percent new)
(كرسي ، 90 بالمائة طاولة جديدة ، 80 بالمائة جديد)
(Wardrobe, 70 percent new.)
(خزانة الملابس ، 70 بالمائة جديدة.)
With this little money,
مع هذا القليل من المال ،
what can I do?
ماذا يمكنني أن أفعل؟
(Contacts)
(جهات الاتصال)
Hey, Li Er.
مرحبًا ، Li Er.
Can you talk right now?
هل يمكنك التحدث الآن؟
Lu Sen, where are you?
لو سين ، أين أنت؟
I was at the orange orchard.
كنت في بستان البرتقال.
Mr. Xie said you have moved out.
قال السيد شيه أنك غادرت.
And you didn't answer my calls.
وأنت لم ترد على مكالماتي.
I'm at a friend's.
أنا عند صديق.
A friend?
صديق؟
Are you at Shan Shan's?
هل أنت في شان شان؟
That's a relief.
هذا مريح.
But why are you calling me at this hour?
لكن لماذا تتصل بي في هذه الساعة؟
Is it because you want to ask about Li Zhan?
هل هذا لأنك تريد أن تسأل عن Li Zhan؟
You went to see him.
ذهبت لرؤيته.
He told me he spied on you...
قال لي إنه تجسس عليك ...
and it seems like he already knows about your condition.
ويبدو أنه يعرف بالفعل حالتك.
How did he know?
كيف عرف؟
I suspect that...
وأظن أن...
it was connected to the hackers who attacked the lab.
كان متصلاً بالمخترقين الذين هاجموا المختبر.
You have to be careful.
عليك أن تكون حذرا.
If he really wants to do something to me again,
إذا كان يريد فعل شيء لي مرة أخرى ،
he wouldn't tell you this.
لن يخبرك بهذا.
Li Zhan.
لي زان.
He's reminding me of something.
إنه يذكرني بشيء ما.
He's reminding you?
إنه يذكرك؟
Do you think...
هل تعتقد...
Li Jing Cheng found out about this,
اكتشف Li Jing Cheng هذا ،
so that's why he took action against you?
لذلك هذا هو السبب في أنه اتخذ إجراءات ضدك؟
No matter what,
بغض النظر،
we must be prepared for the worst.
يجب أن نكون مستعدين للأسوأ.
At the next general meeting,
في الاجتماع العام المقبل ،
I wonder what propaganda Li Jing Cheng will put on.
أتساءل ما هي الدعاية التي سيضعها لي جينغ تشنغ.
I'll try to make it to the meeting...
سأحاول الوصول إلى الاجتماع ...
so I can keep an eye out for you.
حتى أتمكن من متابعتك.
There's something I'd like you to tell Li Zhan.
هناك شيء أود أن تخبرني به لي زان.
Doesn't he always want to know...
ألا يريد دائمًا أن يعرف ...
why I have shut him out...
لماذا أغلقته ...
for all these years?
لكل هذه السنوات؟
It's because of his father.
إنه بسبب والده.
I've been hiding it all these years.
لقد كنت أخفيها طوال هذه السنوات.
Li Zhan.
لي زان.
You can't stay out of this anymore.
لا يمكنك البقاء خارج هذا بعد الآن.
Good morning.
صباح الخير.
Did my uncle kick you out...
هل طردك عمي ...
to sleep out here?
للنوم هنا؟
No.
رقم.
It's nice here.
من الجميل هنا.
He didn't touch you last night, right?
لم يلمسك الليلة الماضية ، أليس كذلك؟
You think too much.
أنت تفكر كثيرا.
I'm going to wash up.
سوف اغتسل.
(Beauty Mask)
(قناع الجمال)
(Hotdog)
(نقانق)
(Rainbow Umbrella)
(مظلة قوس قزح)
Whoever made this umbrella must be a genius.
كل من صنع هذه المظلة يجب أن يكون عبقريا.
You're so happy after a few compliments.
أنت سعيد للغاية بعد مجاملات قليلة.
(Creative Touch Lamp)
(مصباح اللمس الإبداعي)
So you made this too.
اذا انت صنعت هذا ايضا
You have the same temper as your master.
لديك نفس المزاج مثل سيدك.
Lu Sen.
لو سين.
Today, you stood in front of me...
اليوم وقفت أمامي ...
and told me...
وقال لي ...
you wanted to see me.
اردت رؤيتي.
I really wanted to tell you...
أردت حقًا أن أخبرك ...
that I...
أنني...
I was right in front of you.
كنت أمامك مباشرة.
But when you find out about everything,
ولكن عندما تكتشف كل شيء ،
perhaps,
ربما،
I will already be far away.
سأكون بالفعل بعيدا.
I hope that by then,
آمل أنه بحلول ذلك الوقت ،
you'll be in a bigger world,
ستكون في عالم أكبر ،
and you'll come to accept...
وستقبلون ...
that someone has lied to you.
أن أحدهم قد كذب عليك.
I don't want to say sorry,
لا اريد ان اقول اسف
because...
لان...
I like...
انا يعجبني...
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Is there anything else you're not telling me?
هل هناك أي شيء آخر لا تخبرني به؟
This is mine.
هذا لي.
Don't touch it.
لا تلمسه.
I will touch it.
سوف أتطرق إليها.
- Give it to me. - No.
- اعطني اياه.  - رقم.
Give me that.
أعطني هذا.
- Give it to me. - Hold on.
- اعطني اياه.  - يتمسك.
Is that thing for me?
هل هذا الشيء لي؟
(Lu Sen's room)
(غرفة لو سين)
What's in your head?
ماذا يدور في رأسك؟
Umbrella?
مظلة؟
Stuffed bunny?
أرنب محشي؟
And I also heard you say that...
وسمعتك أيضًا تقول ذلك ...
you were right in front of me.
كنت أمامي مباشرة.
What did you mean?
ماذا تقصد؟
I...
أنا...
I meant you were blind.
قصدت أنك كنت أعمى.
What about the latter part?
ماذا عن الجزء الأخير؟
You said you didn't want to apologize to me...
قلت إنك لا تريد الاعتذار لي ...
because you like...
لأنك تحب...
What did you like?
ما الذي أعجبك؟
It didn't record that?
لم يسجل ذلك؟
I meant that I...
قصدت أنني ...
I liked it when you were angry.
لقد أحببت ذلك عندما كنت غاضبًا.
Let go!
اتركه!
These are all my failed work.
هذه هي كل عملي الفاشل.
Actually, there were a lot more,
في الواقع ، كان هناك الكثير ،
but my uncle cleaned them out...
لكن عمي نظفهم ...
because we had a fight before.
لأننا تشاجرنا من قبل.
I risked my life to save this box.
لقد خاطرت بحياتي لإنقاذ هذا الصندوق.
But look.
لكن انظر.
At first glance, this stuffed bunny is useless.
للوهلة الأولى ، هذا الأرنب المحشو عديم الفائدة.
It looks dumb too.
يبدو غبيا أيضا.
But it gives the people a kind of feeling...
لكنه يعطي الناس نوعا من الشعور ...
of being cared for.
من الحصول على الرعاية.
Sure.
بالتأكيد.
Now you can even say the word "dumb".
يمكنك الآن قول كلمة "غبي".
Looks like my inventions...
يبدو أن اختراعاتي ...
aren't useless after all.
ليست عديمة الفائدة بعد كل شيء.
At least they make you human.
على الأقل يجعلونك إنسانًا.
And if I give it some professional knowledge,
وإذا أعطيته بعض المعرفة المهنية ،
I'd say it's still pretty promising.
سأقول أنها لا تزال واعدة جدًا.
Is Mr. Lu trying to make me, the bunny, famous?
هل السيد لو يحاول أن يجعلني الأرنب مشهوراً؟
You don't need my help.
أنت لا تحتاج إلى مساعدتي.
Perhaps you will even be...
ربما ستكون حتى ...
the glory of IMU in the future.
مجد IMU في المستقبل.
Really?
هل حقا؟
Let's sign a contract then.
دعنا نوقع عقدا بعد ذلك.
Sign my hand.
وقع يدي.
You're so childish.
أنت طفولي جدا.
Give me one too.
أعطني واحدة أيضا.
Didn't you say I was childish?
ألم تقل إنني كنت طفولية؟
Sen!
سين!
Mom told me to call you for breakfast.
أخبرتني أمي أن أتصل بك لتناول الإفطار.
Right.
الصحيح.
My dad said,
قال والدي ،
from now on, when you two are inside,
من الآن فصاعدًا ، عندما تكونان بالداخل ،
just leave the door open.
فقط اترك الباب مفتوحا.
It's to get some air.
للحصول على بعض الهواء.
If I'm alone in the room,
إذا كنت وحدي في الغرفة ،
the door can stay closed.
يمكن أن يظل الباب مغلقًا.
Look at you.
انظر لحالك.
Get some air, you said?
هل حصلت على بعض الهواء؟
You barged in even when the door's open.
لقد اقتربت حتى عندما يكون الباب مفتوحا.
Shan Shan.
شان شان.
Are you shy?
هل انت خجول؟
You're not even shy so why would I be?
أنت لست خجولا حتى فلماذا أكون؟
Get in.
أدخل.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Stand still.
تراوح مكانها.
I know you two are friends.
أعلم أنكما صديقان.
I didn't get things wrong.
لم أفهم الأمور.
I like Sen.
أنا أحب السين.
You're okay with that, right?
أنت بخير مع ذلك ، أليس كذلك؟
He isn't my future brother-in-law anyway.
إنه ليس صهري المستقبلي على أي حال.
I can marry him when I grow up.
يمكنني الزواج منه عندما أكبر.
You little...
أنت صغير ...
How are you not embarrassed?
كيف لا تشعر بالحرج؟
But I think that Sen...
لكن أعتقد أن سين ...
doesn't like En Bao a lot.
لا يحب En Bao كثيرًا.
How did you tell?
كيف قلت؟
Why else would he avoid you?
وإلا لماذا يتجنبك؟
Think about it.
فكر في الأمر.
An individual's expression and movement...
تعبير وحركة الفرد ...
can reflect his innermost self, you know?
يمكن أن تعكس ذاته الأعمق ، هل تعلم؟
I don't believe it either.
أنا لا أصدق ذلك أيضًا.
How can anyone not like...
كيف يمكن لأي شخص لا يحب ...
our dear En Bao?
عزيزتنا En Bao؟
Maybe I am wrong...
ربما أكون مخطئا...
about Sen's real attitude.
حول موقف سين الحقيقي.
That's why I think we need to prove it.
لهذا السبب أعتقد أننا بحاجة إلى إثبات ذلك.
Prove it how?
برهنت كيف؟
Sen!
سين!
Here, Lu Sen.
هنا ، لو سين.
Eat more vegetables.
تناول المزيد من الخضروات.
What's wrong? Slow down.
ما هو الخطأ؟  ابطئ.
Let him do it first.
دعه يفعل ذلك أولا.
I'll get you some soup.
سأحضر لك بعض الحساء.
Let me help you.
دعني اساعدك.
It's fine. I'll do it myself.
لا بأس.  سأفعل ذلك بنفسي.
No, thank you.
لا، شكرا.
What are you watching?
ماذا تشاهد؟
Let me watch it too.
دعني اشاهده ايضا
Shan Shan.
شان شان.
Sen.
السناتور.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Hello, Aunt.
مرحبا عمتي.
Shan Shan.
شان شان.
En Bao's grandma called us and said she was sick.
اتصلت بنا جدة إن باو وقالت إنها مريضة.
Your uncle, En Bao and I...
عمك أنا و En Bao ...
are going over there.
ذاهبون هناك.
Why all of a sudden?
لماذا فجأة؟
Is it bad?
هل هذا سيء؟
It's okay. Don't worry.
حسنا.  لا تقلق.
It's probably just an old illness.
ربما يكون مجرد مرض قديم.
Take care of yourselves.
اعتنوا بأنفسكم.
Have a safe trip then.
ثم أتمنى لك رحلة آمنة.
All right.
حسنا.
Is everything okay?
هل كل شيء على ما يرام؟
Yes.
نعم.
Wait.
انتظر.
That's not right.
هذا غير صحيح.
They're not coming home...
لن يعودوا إلى المنزل ...
so it's just me and Lu Sen tonight?
لذلك أنا فقط و لو سين الليلة؟
We'll be all alone.
سنكون بمفردنا.
It's full of chemicals.
إنها مليئة بالمواد الكيميائية.
This one is better.
هذه أفضل.
Let's go.
لنذهب.
Is it really okay to let Shan Shan...
هل من المقبول حقًا السماح لشان شان ...
spend the night alone with that guy?
قضاء الليل وحده مع هذا الرجل؟
It feels inappropriate.
إنه شعور غير مناسب.
It's all right.
كل شيء على ما يرام.
They're both adults.
كلاهما بالغان.
Is your mom's illness...
هل مرض والدتك ...
really that bad?
حقا بهذا السوء؟
How serious is it?
ما مدى جدية ذلك؟
It's nothing serious.
انها غير جدية.
Are you telling me to go alone?
هل تخبرني أن أذهب لوحدي؟
No, what I mean is...
لا ، ما أعنيه هو ...
En Bao should stay at home.
يجب أن يبقى En Bao في المنزل.
Don't think I don't know.
لا أعتقد أنني لا أعرف.
Every day, as long as those two are here,
كل يوم ، طالما هذان الاثنان موجودان هنا ،
you make En Bao third-wheel them...
أنت تجعل من En Bao العجلة الثالثة ...
by clinging onto Lu Sen.
عن طريق التشبث بـ Lu Sen.
Mom, Shan Shan is the third wheel.
أمي ، شان شان هي العجلة الثالثة.
Stop talking nonsense.
توقف عن الكلام هراء.
Do you think they're in love?
هل تعتقد أنهم في حالة حب؟
If they're really dating,
إذا كانا يتواعدان حقًا ،
I will definitely disagree.
أنا بالتأكيد سأختلف.
I'm serious.
أنا جادة.
He doesn't deserve Shan Shan.
لا يستحق شان شان.
Though he's not bad-looking...
على الرغم من أنه ليس سيئ المظهر ...
and he's quite smart.
وهو ذكي جدا.
But...
ولكن...
But what?
ولكن ماذا؟
Let me think of the wording.
اسمحوا لي أن أفكر في الصياغة.
That guy...
ذلك الشاب...
To be frank,
لأكون صريحا،
you're just trying to pick a fight.
أنت فقط تحاول خوض معركة.
Lu Sen is handsome, polite,
لو سين وسيم ، مهذب ،
diligent, and hardworking.
الدؤوب والعمل الدائب.
Most importantly,
الاكثر اهمية،
he can discuss inventions with Shan Shan.
يمكنه مناقشة الاختراعات مع شان شان.
Although he has been fired,
على الرغم من طرده ،
people like him can easily get jobs.
يمكن للأشخاص مثله الحصول على وظائف بسهولة.
He seems pretty all right to me.
يبدو أنه بخير بالنسبة لي.
Let me tell you...
دعني أخبرك...
All right.
حسنا.
I know.
أنا أعرف.
Even if the man closest...
حتى لو كان الرجل الأقرب ...
to perfection in the world stands before you,
إلى الكمال في العالم يقف أمامك ،
you won't let him have Shan Shan.
لن تسمح له بالحصول على شان شان.
Of course.
بالطبع.
She's my niece.
إنها ابنة أخي.
How can I not worry?
كيف لا تقلق؟
I think they're a good match.
أعتقد أنها مباراة جيدة.
I...
أنا...
I forgot to buy you slippers.
لقد نسيت أن أشتري لك النعال.
Shan Shan.
شان شان.
I'm starving.
أنا جائع.
Are you starving?
هل تتضور جوعا؟
But we need the slippers.
لكننا نحتاج النعال.
Dad, I'm so tired.
أبي ، أنا متعب للغاية.
Can you hold me?
يمكنك عقد لي؟
No, Xiao Dong.
لا ، شياو دونغ.
You're all grown up now,
لقد كبرت الآن ،
a real man.
رجل حقيقي.
We'll be home soon.
سنعود إلى المنزل قريبًا.
Hold this.
امسك هذا.
Put me down.
انزلني.
- Put me down. - No.
- انزلني.  - رقم.
You're so annoying.
انت مزعج جدا.
Don't let anyone see me.
لا تدع أي شخص يراني.
I'll hit you.
سوف أضربك.
My head!
رأسي!
Take off your shoes.
اخلع حذائك.
(Lu Sen's room)
(غرفة لو سين)
He's gone.
لقد رحل.
Sixty-five seconds.
خمس وستون ثانية.
You left me out here for 65 seconds.
لقد تركتني هنا لمدة 65 ثانية.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Well...
نحن سوف...
When you were pretending to be Friday,
عندما كنت تتظاهر بأنك يوم الجمعة ،
I wanted to give them to you.
أردت أن أعطيهم لك.
Who would've known...
من كان سيعرف ...
they belonged to you all along.
كانوا ينتمون لك طوال الوقت.
So?
لذا؟
So...
لذا...
The light is on.
الضوء مضاء.
Do you know what that means?
هل تعرف ماذا يعني هذا؟
What?
ماذا؟
It means that...
هذا يعني انه...
I forgive you.
أنا أسامحكم.
Shan Shan.
شان شان.
Let's make up.
دعنا نتفاهم.
Give me a hug.
احضني.
It's done.
تم التنفيذ.
I know Mr. Si called you just now.
أعلم أن السيد سي اتصل بك الآن.
Did something happen to the company?
هل حدث شيء للشركة؟
No, it's just some daily reports.
لا ، إنها فقط بعض التقارير اليومية.
Okay.
تمام.
Look at you.
انظر لحالك.
This was you when you first met Mr. Si.
كان هذا أنت عندما قابلت السيد سي لأول مرة.
Lu Sen.
لو سين.
What about you?
وماذا عنك؟
Don't touch my hair.
لا تلمس شعري.
My arm.
ذراعي.
I...
أنا...
I'm going to bed.
انا ذاهب الى السرير.
I want you to leave.
اريد منك ان تغادر.
I want to tell you a story.
اريد ان اقول لك قصة.
Then I want a story about the bunny.
ثم أريد قصة عن الأرنب.
Once upon a time,
كان ياما كان،
there was a bunny.
كان هناك أرنب.
It learned the secret...
علمت السر ...
that it could eat the moon in the sky.
أنه يمكن أن يأكل القمر في السماء.
When the moon was full,
عندما كان القمر بدرا ،
he climbed up the hill,
تسلق التل ،
reached out,
وصلت ،
took the moon and put it in its mouth.
أخذ القمر ووضعه في فمه.
The moon tasted really sweet.
طعم القمر حلو حقا.
The bunny is gluttonous.
الأرنب شره.
It sat on the hillside and waited...
جلس على جانب التل وانتظر ...
while the moon was still crescent.
بينما كان القمر لا يزال هلالًا.
Then, it bumped...
ثم اصطدمت ...
into a little red-tailed fox.
إلى ثعلب صغير أحمر الذيل.
That bunny...
هذا الأرنب ...
stuttered.
متلعثم.
It wanted to let the fox have the moon,
أرادت السماح للثعلب بالقمر ،
but it couldn't make up its mind.
لكنها لم تستطع اتخاذ قرار.
"Let me say it first."
"دعني أقولها أولاً".
The fox said,
قال الثعلب ،
"I come here every night because..."
"آتي إلى هنا كل ليلة لأن ..."
The fox's face turned so red.
تحول وجه الثعلب إلى الأحمر.
It's as red as its fur.
إنه أحمر مثل فراءه.
"It is because..."
"هذا بسبب ..."
"I like you a lot, bunny."
"أنا معجب بك كثيرًا يا أرنب."
The bunny was shy.
كان الأرنب خجولا.
It said,
وقال انه،
"I like you too."
"أنامعجب بك أيضا."
Little fox heard it...
سمعها الثعلب الصغير ...
and it jumped for joy.
وقفز من أجل الفرح.
It reached out...
وصلت ...
and got many stars on the hillside.
وحصلت على العديد من النجوم على منحدر التل.
It picked them up with his two little paws...
حملهم مع اثنين من الكفوف الصغيرة ...
and gave them to the bunny.
وأعطاهم للأرنب.
He said,
هو قال،
"Try them."
"جربهم."
"I was too shy to tell you before."
"كنت خجولا جدا لأخبرك من قبل."
"You can eat the stars on the hill."
"يمكنك أن تأكل النجوم على التل."
"They taste very sweet."
"طعمها حلو جدا."
The bunny took a star...
أخذ الأرنب نجمة ...
and put it in its mouth.
ووضعه في فمه.
It's really sweet.
انها حقا حلوة.
Good night.
طاب مساؤك.
My little bunny.
بلدي الأرنب الصغير.
The little fox...
الثعلب الصغير ...
will get you all the stars...
سوف تحصل على كل النجوم ...
in the sky.
في السماء.